# NATALIE CYGAN



cygann@stanford.edu



(940) 536-8620



nataliecygan.com



531 Lasuen Mall P.O. Box 15166 Stanford, CA 94305

### PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

Extensive programming experience in C++, C, Python, and Java. Project experience with Swift, React Native, and HTML/CSS.

## TOOLS/LIBRARIES

PyTorch, NumPy, Jupyter Notebook, OpenCV, LaTeX, Unix, Google Cloud Platform

Visualization: Plotly, Dash, Streamlit

#### LANGUAGES

Working proficiency in French

#### VOLUNTEER/OUTREACH

Stanford Society of Women Engineers
Outreach Intern: Organized outreach
events directed at young girls K-12 to
increase female representation in STEM.

Denton Girls + Code: Created an organization to introduce local middle school girls to computer science skills through after school workshops in my hometown.

Code in Place: Worked with a team of Stanford professors and section leaders to launch a 5-week MOOC version of Stanford's introductory computer science class to 10,000 students during the COVID-19 lockdown. Taught a weekly discussion section over zoom as a part of the teaching team.

## EDUCATION

## Stanford University, Stanford, CA

## **B.S Computer Science**

SEPTEMBER 2017 - DECEMBER 2021

**Relevant completed coursework**: Computer Systems, Linear Algebra, Computer Vision, Artificial Intelligence, Deep Generative Models, Neural Networks, Digital Systems Architecture, Operating Systems, Human-Computer interaction, Electronics.

**Upcoming 2020-2021**: Natural Language Processing, Information Theory, Machine Learning, Computer and Network Security.

## EXPERIENCE

## Software Engineering Intern

Red Leader Technologies, Palo Alto, CA

JUNE 2020 - DECEMBER 2020

- Six month full-time internship.
- Used Python and Streamlit to develop upon a lidar system control dashboard, adding logging, interactive plots, and statistics for live telemetry data.
- Built an end-to-end computer vision application using OpenCV and Plotly Dash to emperically characterize transmitted laser patterns in the far-field from an image. Used in calibration and optics development.
- Assisted in writing device firmware in C to report telemetry data and interact with various sensors.
- Created a point cloud tools library in Python for a variety of tasks such as filtering and registration.
- Responsible for developing point cloud visualizations and perception tasks used for critical company demos.

## Software Engineering Intern

Google, Sunnyvale, CA

JUNE 2019 - SEPTEMBER 2019

- Intern on the Visual Semantic Service team, providing computer vision for all Google products.
- I modernized heavily used face feature landmarking software by researching active shape models, and rewriting the pipeline with optimized math libraries (C++, Eigen) and standardized programming style.
- Introduced unit tests, wrote testing tools, and created documentation for further developing the FaceSDK pipeline.

### CS 106 Section Leader

#### Stanford University, Stanford, CA

APRIL 2018 - JANUARY 2020

- Taught weekly discussion sections for students in CS 106A, CS 106B, and CS 106X in Java, Python, and C++.
- Graded student homework assignments with extensive feedback on code functionality and style, and held 15-minute code individual code review sessions with them.
- Held weekly office hour shifts to help students debug their code and understand course material. Helped with preflighting new assignments and maintaining internal documentation for other section leaders.
- Held review sessions for student exams, and gave a guest lecture in class.
- Led workshops and evaluations involved in the training of new section leaders.

## PROJECTS

# Learning to Groove: Conditional Melody Generation from Authentic Basslines

OCTOBER 2019 - DECEMBER 2019

- Final project for CS 236: Deep Generative Models.
- Generated artificial music tracks with a dual LSTM model: a bassline model that is trained first and provides rich encodings, and a melody model that conditions generation upon those bass encodings. We also present a novel encoding scheme for representing polyphonic music.

### Facial and Portrait Aware Artistic Style Transfer

APRIL 2019 - JUNE 2019

- Capstone project for CS 231N: Convolutional Neural Networks for Visual Recognition.
- Improved upon canonical artistic style transfer implementations by introducing a subject-background segmentation step and additional training loss term that emphasizes style in the background in order to preserve the integrity of facial characteristics.